維吉尼亞州 漢普頓
Hampton,virginia
這些實驗證明 有幾個要素非常明顯
now, from these experiments, A few factors became evident.
其中一個是 自有人類以來 連環殺手就已經存在於我們身邊
One was the realization That serial killers have been with us Since the dawn of man.
求你了 放他走吧
Please, let him go.
什麼東西都給你 隨便拿
Take whatever you want, take anything,
求你放了我兒子吧
But please let my son go.
我是教授 名叫James Fallon
My name is professor james fallon.
我是科學家 神經系統科學家
I'm a scientist-- neuroscientist--
我研究人類的腦部
And i study the human brain.
它是一個複雜 有時甚至可以致命的機器
It is a complex and sometimes lethal machine.
在一次"盲法"試驗 同事給了我70份MRI腦部掃瞄
In a blind experiment, colleagues sent me 70 mri brain scans,
而我完全不知道這些掃瞄是屬於哪個人
And i had no idea who these brains belonged to.
有些很正常 有的是精神分裂癥患者的
Some were normals, some were schizophrenics,
有的是殺手的
And some were killers.
我把他們全部做分析
I analyzed all of them,
判斷其中5個是精神病患者的腦部
5 of which i determined were the brains of psychopaths.
但事實上 這5個是知名連環殺手的腦部
And it turned out that, indeed, These 5 were the brains of serial killers, Some of whom you know.
通過這類研究
In studies such as these,
研究這些生物學的要素
One looks at the biological factors...
既是遺傳學也是腦部病理學的範疇
That is, the genetics and also the brain pathology.
我們所鑒定的這5個腦部 額眶部皮質都有損傷
The 5 brains we identified All had damage to the orbital cortex,
也就是眼部上方的區域
Which is right above the eyes.
單胺氧化?的高危對偶基因
Now, high-risk allele of the monoamine oxidase a,
單胺氧化?a也許同樣存在於這些人的體內
The maoa gene May also be present in these people,
那就是關鍵
And that's key.
在高危基因的作用下
Now, under the effects of the high-risk gene,
精神病患者的腦部在胎兒發育過程中
The brain of the psychopath was bathed
浸泡了過多5-羥色胺
In way too much serotonin during fetal development.
成人之後
As an adult,
腦部對5-羥色胺的鎮靜作用變得麻木
This brain is now numb To seratonin's calming effects.
於是最危險的要素已經到位
The first dangerous elements are now in place.
傷害已造成
The damage is done.
這就是產生災難的方法
Now, this is a recipe for catastrophe.
當胎兒分娩的那天
So when the fetus reaches the day of labor,
潛在的連環殺手就誕生了
The potential serial killer is born.
媽媽
Mom! uhh--
Mom!
維吉尼亞州 漢普頓 三天後
Hampton,Virginia 3days later
你週末過得怎樣?
hey, how was your weekend?
異常充實啊 全家人都被殺了?
Uh, scary yet informative. was the whole family killed?
Hudson 這是Spencer Reid博士
Hudson, this is dr. spencer reid.
這位是外勤探員Anne Hudson
Field agent anne hudson.
這個家庭堛漱鷟辿b伊拉克服役
The, uh, father is serving in iraq.
三晚前 警察發現他的家人被埋在這
3 nights ago the cops found his family buried over there.
埋葬?
Buried?
鄰居聽到狗吠 過來看
The neighbors heard the dog barking, came over,
看到它正扒拉著墓
And he was scratching at the grave.
Lucy 年齡最大的孩子 還穿著泳衣
Lucy, their oldest child, she's still in her swimsuit.
父親知道了嗎?
What does the father know?
知道一點 他當時正外出巡邏
some of it. he was on patrol.
他的部隊用了幾天時間才找到他
Took his unit a couple of days to reach him.
他今天抵達
He arrives today.
去年Williams家族也是以同樣的方式 被殺和被發現
Last year the Williams family Was killed and found exactly the same way.
他們住在Newport News
They lived in Newport News.
父親Dan Williams當時正在海外服役
The father, dan Williams, was also serving overseas.
警局快扛不住了 受到來自軍方的巨大壓力
Now, the police are overwhelmed And getting serious heat from the military.
我們需要盡快得出答案
We need some answers fast.
媒體也是
as do the media.
他們已經把案件歸為連環殺手所為
They're already calling this the work of a serial killer.
他們沒說錯 的確是這樣
They're right. it is.
為什麼要埋葬他們呢?
But why bury them?
不可能是為了隱藏屍體啊
I mean, it can't be to hide the bodies.
是懊悔的表現
it's a sign of remorse.
當他們不再感到懊悔 就會再次開始殺戮
And when they're done being remorseful, This will happen again.
犯罪心理 第五季 第8集
Criminal Minds S05E08
"人們從不輕易承認他人的睿智"
"man usually avoids attributing cleverness to somebody else,
"除非棋逢敵手"
Unless it's an enemy."
艾伯特·愛因斯坦
Albert einstein.
沒有掙扎的痕跡
no sign of a struggle.
疑犯把槍抵在她孩子的頭上
Unsub holds a gun to one of her kids' head.
她還能怎麼做?
What can she do?
足印是Paul的
Footprints belong to paul.
他當時脫身了
Somehow he managed to get away.
媽媽首先被殺 然後是最小的孩子
Mom gets it first, then the youngest.
他藏在主人房
He hides in the master bedroom,
疑犯找到他 一槍斃命
The unsub finds him and shoots him.
然後把他抱到後院
And carries him out to the backyard.
但母親不是這樣 她是被拖出去的
But not the mother. she's dragged out.
疑犯動作迅速熟練
It's quick and proficient.
只是相對於母親和男孩而言
For the mother and the boys, maybe.
但Lucy是淹死的 而不是被槍殺
But lucy's drowned and not shot.
為什麼要改變作案手法?
Why the change in m.o.?
F-22猛禽戰鬥機
f-22 raptor.
是啊 這媟|變得更熱鬧更忙碌
Yeah. it's about to get way louder and much busier.
明天是慶祝蘭利成立50週年的空軍表演
Tomorrow is langley's 50th anniversary air show.
第一個遇害家庭的父親Dan Williams
The father of the first family killed--dan Williams,
他在哪?
Where is he now?
他又被派到伊拉克去了
He put in for another tour of iraq.
兩個月前被簡單爆炸裝置殺死
An i.e.d. killed him 2 months ago.
兇手知道父親在海外服役
Whoever did this Knew both fathers were serving overseas.
Laura Downey的結婚戒指不見了
Laura downey's wedding rings are missing.
還有其他東西遺失嗎?
Any other valuables?
我們得問她丈夫才知道
We'll have to ask the husband.
在Williams的案件 只有珠寶和手錶失蹤
From the Williams home, Only jewelry and watches were missing.
疑犯只帶走輕便的東西 意味著他是步行的
The unsub only took what he can carry, Which means he's most likely on foot.
廚房的牆壁上有張照片
There was a photo on the wall in the kitchen.
我想去看看
I'd like to see it.
沒問題
Sure.
在Williams的案件 沒有性侵犯的跡象
There's no sign of sexual assault In the Williams case.
Lucy呢?
what about lucy?
根據法醫的報告 也沒有
Nothing on the coroner's report.
也許是有幾個疑犯?
Multiple suspects?
母親被拖出房子
The mother was dragged out of the house.
如果是多人作案
If it had been multiple suspects,
就能抬起她
They probably would have carried her.
他知道父親不在
He knew the father was absent,
所以最大的威脅不在
Therefore the dominant threat was absent.
我們要找的可能是獨自作案
So we could be looking for a single suspect.
沒有強行進入的跡象
No sign of forced entry.
沒有必要 Lucy在泳池
No need. lucy was in the pool,
後門開著 疑犯直接進來就是了
Back door was open. the unsub walked right in.
意味著Lucy是最後死的
That means lucy probably died last.
不管是哪種情況 這女孩始終是窒息而死 而不是被槍殺
In both cases the girls were suffocated And not shot.
我認為這不是巧合
i don't think it's a coincidence.
Garcia 說吧
Hey, garcia. you're on speaker.
我們剛接到維吉尼亞州 極限管理重罪犯監獄的電話
We just got a call From virginia super max prison.
其中一個犯人在過去兩天 接到兩封信
One of the inmates there Has received 2 envelopes in the last 2 days.
第一封信裝了Newport News謀殺案的剪報
First envelope had clippings of the Newport News killings.
第二封信是Downey謀殺案的視頻剪輯
Second envelope had media clippings of the downey family.
第二封信媮晹陰i便條 寫著 "看看我都幹了什麼"
In the second envelope was a note saying, "look at what i've done,"
兩封信署名"仰慕者"
and both pieces of mail Have been signed by "an admirer."
是哪個犯人?
Who's the inmate?
這就是問題...
That's the part that...
Karl Arnold
Karl arnold.
- 狡狐? - 他又出現了
The fox? he's back.
好的 謝謝
Ok, thanks.
滅門 父親外出 結婚戒指
Family annihilator, absent father, wedding rings.
太相似
It's similar.
像什麼?
To what?
4年前 Karl Arnold 外號"狡狐" 屠殺了8個家庭
4 years ago, Karl arnold, aka the fox, Killed 8 families.
就像這案件一樣 他拿走結婚戒指
Just like this case, he took wedding rings,
只不過他是當作戰利品拿走
Only he took them as trophies.
他躲在那些家庭外的灌木叢
he'd hide in the bushes outside the homes.
我觀察他們很多天
And i watched them... for a number of days.
通常是在夜晚
Always at night.
看著他們怎麼生活
Saw how they lived...
有多麼相愛
How they loved.
在下一個夜晚 我就把他們分開
I would keep them apart until the last night.
我把他們逐一帶到地庫
Then i would bring them, one by one, Down to the basement,
年紀最小的最先
The youngest first.
父親是壓軸
The father last.
為什麼 Karl
Why, Karl?
好讓他看看發生了什麼
So he could see what happens...
看看家庭支柱不夠強壯 家人會變得如何悲慘
To families When the head of household isn't strong.
妻子們死去
Wives wither...
孩子夭折
Children perish.
我們要面對的是模仿作案?
So, we're working with a copycat here?
現在還言之過早
It's too early to assume anything.
會影響側寫的準確性
It could bias the profile.
更別提警察 媒體 甚至軍方的反應
Not to mention the police, the media, and the military Would jump all over it.
在我們確定前 這信息只有我們7個人知道就好
Until we're positive, none of this information leaves the 7 of us.
Hotch 是你在Arnold的審判上作證
Hotch, you gave evidence at arnold's trial.
你應該去見見他
I think you should go see him.
- 我想帶上Prentiss - 走吧
I'd like to take prentiss with me. Let's go.
讓Garcia檢查Arnold監獄過去四年內
Have garcia check on all of arnold's prison correspondence
所有信件及探訪者
And visitors for the last 4 years.
好的 Joseph Downey上校剛到站
Ok. captain joseph downey has arrived back at the station.
維吉尼亞州警察局
virginia state police
Downey上校 請坐
captain downey, please, sit.
謝了 我沒事
Thank you, i'm fine.
告訴我吧
Tell me everything.
三天前 晚上9:30左右
At around 9:30 3 nights ago,
你的鄰居報案...
Your neighbors called police when...
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
長官
Sir.
我們相信這是連環殺手干的
We believe it was the work of a serial killer.
抱歉 我的鄰居 Jack和Penny...
I'm sorry. my neighbors, uh, jack and penny--
Downey上校…
Captain downey...
你的家人被謀殺了
Your family was murdered.
全部都不在了
All of them.
需要我們替你打電話給什麼人嗎？
Is there someone you'd like us to call?
打給...不 不 我...
Uh, call, um--no, no. i, uh...
我想馬上回家
I--i'd like to go home now.
Downey上校 Downey上校 上校...
Captain downey. captain downey. captain d--
沒事
Ok.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
很替你難過
I'm so sorry.
維吉尼亞州 Red Onion極限管理重罪犯監獄
red onion super max prison virginia
為什麼等了一年才給Karl寄信
So why wait a year to send Karl a note,
除非他們一直有聯繫
Unless they were communicating the whole time?
這是第一件需要查明的事
That's the first thing we need to find out.
但Karl很自負
But Karl has a big ego.
要他回答問題就得先滿足他的疑問
He's gonna want to answer a question with a question.
他想知道的第一件事會是 我為什麼沒戴著婚戒
The first thing he's gonna want to know Is why i'm not wearing my wedding ring.
然後就會把注意力轉到你身上
And then he will turn his attention to you.
所以你要帶上我
So that's why you brought me along.
你的存在會令他放下戒心
Your presence will throw him off guard.
然後他會向你生動地描述
Then he's gonna want to describe to you in graphic detail
他對那些家庭犯下的每一個性行為
Every sexual act he committed with the families.
為了嚇倒我?
To freak me out?
把你拖進他的幻想世界
To pull you into his fantasy.
控制室 打開16號門
Control, open on 16.
走吧
go ahead
看著前面
Keep your eyes forward.
他最想看的 肯定是孩子們的照片
More than anything, he's going to want to see the images of the children.
我們不能給他
We can't give him that.
我們得給他一點甜頭 不然就沒法從他身上得到什麼
We have to give him something or we'll get nothing from him.
來啊
Come on!
那不是...
Isn't that, uh--
加勒特疼痛 沒關係 那是鋼化玻璃 （腰肌和骨骼疼痛的一種）
Garrett pain. that's reinforced glass.
說得輕巧 他可是肢解了14個女人
Easy for you to say. he tore apart 14 women.
把15號牢房門打開
open on 15.
喔 寶貝
whoa, baby!
你好 Karl
Hello, Karl.
探員Hotchner
Agent hotchner.
我怎麼沒聽說你還會帶一個這麼...
I wasn't informed you were bring in a, uh...
他們只說會來兩個探員
They just said two agents.
- 這位是探員... - Emily
This is agent-- Emily...
Prentiss
Prentiss.
我知道你的一切
I know all about you.
如果不明嫌犯模仿"狡狐"作案
If this unsub's copying the fox,
咱們就要從這個角度對他進行側寫
Then we profile him like the fox.
Karl Arnold當時是在做心理幫助咨詢對吧
?????system,right
沒錯 這也就給他間接監視 確定 瞭解 受害者提供了非常便利的條件
Yeah. which made it easy for him to watch, target, And learn about the victims from a distance.
而且這個身份也不會引人懷疑
Yeah, it also made him hard to find.
和"狡狐"一樣 這回的嫌犯也是 找到了很好的掩飾
Like the fox, our man here found a way To hide in plain sight.
但是他所涉及的家庭職業構成完全不同
But he's pulling from 2 completely different units.
Williams是個醫生 Downey是個軍官
Williams a medic, downey an army captain.
有人知道他們和軍隊的關係
Someone knew of that military connection.
這兩次都是在父親被調走之後的一個月發生的
Both families were attacked within a month of the fathers being deployed.
給予他們充足的時間先適應 父親不在身邊的新生活
Gave them time to settle in, Get comfortable that the fathers weren't there.
等到"狡狐"闖進房子堶 就開始和他們一起居住
And once inside the home, the fox would live with the families
進而開始扮演父親的角色
And then become the father.
可這個不明嫌犯並非如此
But not this unsub.
他只是進去把家人分開再殺害
He just walked in and dispensed with the family.
同一屋檐下生活的場景根本 不曾出現在他的腦海當中
Living with them wasn't part of the fantasy.
探員Rossi
agent rossi.
這是你要的圖片
The picture you requested.
都靠你我們才從這張合影上取下了很多指紋
Thanks to you, we pulled some prints off it.
所有的指紋都在Lucy身上
And all the prints were on lucy.
子彈卻直接射向父親
The bullet hit the father dead center.
指紋和Newport News兇殺案相吻合
The prints match that of the Newport News killings.
是同一人所為
It's the same killer.
像"狡狐"那樣的反家庭分子 一般都喜歡先從一個身上下手
Family annihilators like the fox, they start with one victim.
等到他們滿意了
And once they feel capable,
再對下一個下手
They move on to a second victim.
一般不會同一時間全部殺死
They don't start with entire families.
也就是說還有許多受害者 只是我們還沒找到
There are more victims. we just haven't found them yet.
Karl 看來你有了個粉絲
Karl, it appears you have a fan.
崇拜者
Admirer.
不是粉絲
Not a fan.
很大區別呢 對吧
Big difference. right?
這是你頭一次和你的崇拜者聯繫嗎?
Is this the first time you've been contacted by your admirer?
我有好多粉絲呢
I have many fans.
還有個人主頁
Even my own website.
你有嗎你
Don't you?
他們問的問題肯定會讓你們大吃一驚
You'd be astounded At some of the questions they ask.
我還把這些整理了一個日誌呢 想不想讀一讀啊
I make a log of all of them. Would you like to read some?
我非常樂意
I would love to.
真的?
You'd love to?
好吧
Yes.
這
Here.
拿去看吧
Look.
我一會再看
Maybe later.
你的崇拜者像你一樣 專取別人的婚戒
Your admirer is taking wedding rings, Just like you.
不過可能原因不相同
But maybe not for the same reason.
是啊 就像是你也拿走了我收藏的所有婚戒
Like how you took all of mine.
不過你雖然拿走了我的
You took mine.
但我也看到 你丟了你的
But i see... you lost yours.
8枚戒指 4個家庭
8 rings, 4 families.
還是說你一家只取了一枚
Or was it one ring for each family?
你的婚戒怎麼沒的呢
How'd you come to lose your ring?
哦 別跟我說是受了什麼工傷
wait, don't tell me. A casualty of the job.
我的工作就是把你送進這堥
My job is what put you in here.
的確
True.
不過 家庭破裂倒霉的是孩子 我說的對吧?
But then, it's the children Who suffer most. wouldn't you agree?
這點你應該比我更清楚
You'd know more about that than me.
所以你得來向我討教
Which is why you came to me.
這個忙我還是幫得上的 探員Hotchner
I can help you with that, agent hotchner.
絕對能幫
I certainly can.
不過我要看那些照片
But i'll need to see those photos.
可以嗎
May i?
借一步說話
A word?
Emily 有什麼問題嗎
Is there a problem, emily?
沒問題 Karl
There's no problem, Karl.
我們不能給他看這些
We cannot show him these.
這些圖片可能就是他的動機起源 也是我們查案的切入點
These images will be his undoing And our way in.
但是他們不是普通的照片
But they're not just images.
這些只是照片
That's exactly what they are.
我們不能這樣利用Lucy
We can't use lucy like that.
想要有所得 就得有所捨棄
It's a tradeoff we have to make.
難道我們真的要用一個12歲女孩 穿著泳衣的屍體照片當做誘餌
So, we are using a dead 12-year-old girl in a bathing suit As a bargaining chip?
為了什麼?
for what?
但是對他來說這圖片也非同小可
To him it's not just a photograph.
它的意義非凡 而我們太需要這些信息了
It's much, much more, and we need to know what.
你聽我說 我...
Look, i'm...
我之前從來沒幹過這些
I've never done this before.
現在你也不必勉強
And you don't have to now.
不 我必須要做
Yes, i do.
那好 一旦我發覺他要說什麼了 我就先離開
All right. when i feel he's ready to talk, I'll leave the room.
你來讓他開口
You get him talking.
不論他做什麼 不論你怎麼想 都一定要堅持住
Whatever he does, whatever you feel, Just stay on script.
我們要知道他為什麼殺了那些家庭
We need to know why he killed those families.
他有幾個來訪者
he's had a smattering of visits,
還有一些工作分配聯絡
A couple of whack jobs contact him,
不過這些都與崇拜者無關
But nothing as direct as this admirer person.
那照片上面的指紋呢
how are we doing on the prints on the picture?
哦 我還在查
Oh. i'm still running them.
你那邊怎麼樣
How are you holding up?
軍旅家庭 一般都惶恐度日
Military families, they always fear the worst.
恐怕哪一天父親就回不來了
They know their men may not return,
但是 這一次卻是父親失去了整個家庭
But this-- To see a father lose so much.
我真希望能做點什麼
I wish i had something for you.
可是我真的找不到任何 能把這些家庭聯繫起來的
I truly cannot find a damn thing That connects these families.
軍人和家屬之間相隔萬里
Geographically, both of them Are thousands of miles away from their family.
能不能找到他們之間的聯絡 電郵 信件或者是電話
Communication's all they had-- Emails, phone calls, letters.
但是這都屬於軍事通信
But that's military communication.
即便家屬的私人通信 也需要授權才能進入
Even between families, it requires a kind of juice i'm not allowed to use.
不會吧 你可是侵入過FBI數據庫的啊
Come on. you hacked into the fbi database.
是啊 我工作就這麼來的嘛
And they gave me a job.
而且我還很喜歡這工作
And i like my job.
我也很珍惜自己的小命
And i like my life.
那好吧 我這邊疏通一下
All right, i'll make some inquiries.
- 先謝謝啦 保重 - 拜
Ok. do that. take care. Bye.
Lucy是最後一個死的 而且一個人
So lucy dies last, alone.
單獨這個說明不了什麼
This by itself doesn't really mean anything,
但是如果我們再仔細看看Williams的檔案
But when we look again at the Williams file,
我們發現入室者留下最多的指紋 也都集中在Karen Williams的房間
We notice that the majority of the foreign fingerprints Came from karen Williams' room,
也就是說嫌犯大多數時間都和Karen在一起
Which means the unsub spent most of his time in there with karen.
所以他必須要把她與其他家庭成員隔離開
Then he must have separated her from the rest of the family.
Lucy Downey那時候已經在泳池堣F
Lucy downey was already in the pool.
已經和家人隔離開就不用嫌犯費神了
That much was done for the unsub.
可是不明嫌犯仍然受到某種強迫癥的驅使
Then this unsub is driven by some other kind of compulsion,
一些其他的心理需求
Some other need.
Hotch說的沒錯 這絕不是巧合 可能是潛在的作案特徵
Hotch was right. this isn't a coincidence. It's a possible signature.
長官 我明白 但是有兩家人都死了
Sir, i know that, but two families have died.
我明白這不合乎規定 但是...
No, i realize this breaks protocol, but--
不 我們想要的只是阻止類似慘案再次發生
No, all we want is to stop this from happening again.
長官 我向您保證 探員Garcia絕不會讓您失望
Sir, i promise you, agent garcia is the best we have.
好的 謝謝您
Ok. thank you.
我們需要以每一個受害者為中心
We need to look at each of the victims as a hub,
去研究他們家庭之外的生活
With lives outside of their own families.
所有人都有家庭以外的生活和社交圈
Well, each one of them has their own connections outside the family.
學校 朋友 老師 生意夥伴
School, friends, tutors, business colleagues.
所有這些人都有辦法進入他們家
And each one of these people Are considered access points back to the family.
不過可能需要好幾周
That could take weeks.
至少從懊悔到再起殺意前 我們還有時間
Well, you have time. From remorse to the desire to kill again
這期間有可能嫌犯經歷情緒上的波動
The unsub will go through a gamut of emotions.
也可能在他再次動殺人念頭前 又要過一年
It could be another year before the unsub feels the desire to kill again.
鑒於罪行極為嚴重
As horrific as these crimes are,
這堥S辦法跟他耗上這麼久
This city doesn't have the resources to commit that amount of time.
我們已得到授權 現在能得到 所有關於父親的軍事記錄
We have full access to all military records for the fathers.
所以 至少現在我們能瞭解不同家庭的核心了
Well, now at least We have access to the main hub between families.
父親
The dads.
那好吧 咱們先找出他們有什麼聯繫
All right, well, let's find out What connects them.
站起來
Stand up.
你想看 是不是
You want to see, don't you?
迫不及待
Very much.
我們會給你看
We're gonna show you.
這堿ODowney家的房子
This is the home of the downey family.
這家有3個孩子
There were 3 children.
他們都多大?
How old are the children?
分別12歲 9歲和4歲 一女兩男
12, 9, and 4. a girl and two boys.
他們在哪堻Q發現?
Where were they found?
那邊
Over there.
被埋起來的
Buried.
有趣
Interesting.
孩子母親Laura還有兩個男孩在屋堻Q殺
Laura, the mother, and the two boys were killed In the house.
那女兒呢?
The daughter?
這堿O母親和小兒子被殺的地方
This is where the mother and the youngest son were killed.
另一個男孩在臥室衣櫥堶掖Q射殺
The other boy was shot in the bedroom closet.
- 父親到哪堨h了 - 在國外
Where's the father? overseas.
嫌犯知道這個
The killer knows this.
他對這個家庭非常瞭解
He knows everything about this family,
他仔細觀察他們的每一個舉動 確保自己達到目的
And he watches their every move To be sure he achieves what he needs.
你肯定不知道他是怎麼知道父親不在
You have no idea how he knows The father is gone
怎麼把目光放到這一家的
Or how he targets these families,
這些個怎麼
And the how.
才是解決問題的關鍵
That's the key.
這也是為什麼他想要與我並駕齊驅
The how... Is why he... Was able to catch me.
你暗中觀察了這些家庭很多天
You watched the families for days.
很多周
Weeks.
我要瞭解他們
I got to know them.
但是你們要找的人並不是這樣
But not your guy.
他不需要那麼多周 如果他準備了那麼久 肯定會在屋子埵h呆一會
He doesn't need weeks. if he did, he'd stay longer.
為什麼?
Why?
因為他要好好享受一番
So he can enjoy them.
但我不明白的是
But what i don't understand--
為什麼他不把孩子與大人分開
Is why he didn't separate the children.
正是
Exactly.
因為那麼做會更好地掌控局勢 不會有出錯的餘地
That way you have more control. no room for error.
為什麼他不把那些孩子帶到另外一間屋
Why he didn't put the boys in separate rooms
告訴他們 "如果你們哭的話"
and say, If you cry...
"我就殺了你們媽媽"
I'll have to kill mommy.
告訴我
Tell me...
那個女孩是怎麼死的
How did the girl die?
她是被淹死的
She was drowned.
而其他的是被射殺的
Yet the others were shot.
能讓我看一眼她的照片麼?
May i see her?
這女孩哪點這麼吸引你了?
What's so special about the girl?
兇手之所以要悶死她
To suffocate her.
是為了享受死者嚥下最後一口氣時 帶給自己的快感
To feel the life leave her body Means everything to the man who did this.
對你而言也許是這樣 但不是兇手
To you, maybe, but not to this killer.
你們並不一樣
Not in the same way.
我殺人只是為了讓孩子看看 他們的父親有多無能
All i did was show them how weak fathers could be.
僅此而已
That's all.
你在殺每個孩子之前都猥褻了他們
Every child you killed you abused physically.
但這人卻沒有
For this man, there is no sexual gratification.
不管怎樣 我免去了那些父親們的痛苦
At least i spared the fathers The grief of living.
求你了...求求你了
Please... Please don't do this.
走吧 去洗把澡
Come on. let's get you cleaned up.
Dani! 我沒告訴過你要鎖上門麼?
Dani! didn't i tell you to always lock the door!
Nick 把鞋脫了!
Nick, cleats off!
Dani!你在哪?
Dani! where are you?
Dani?
媽媽?
Mom?
求你了 別
Please don't--
求你了...
Please...
媽媽...
Mom...
- 女孩是被悶死的 而不是槍擊 對吧? - 是的
The girl was suffocated, not shot, right? yes.
和上兩起案子一樣
Just like the other two.
她叫Dani 14歲
Her name is Dani. she's 14.
她父親呢?
and the father?
在阿富汗
Afghanistan.
這可以排除是贖罪的表現了吧?
Does this rule out remorse?
我想是的
Yes, it does.
現在怎麼辦?
So what is it now?
作案的升級說明嫌疑犯心理再次受到衝擊
The escalation between kills Indicates a major psychological break.
為什麼說又升級了?
How is it escalated?
作案間隔時間從1年變成了3天
The timeframe between kills Has gone from a year to just 3 days.
嫌犯一定發生了什麼大事
For the unsub, something has dramatically changed.
某些外部原因刺激到了嫌犯
Some kind of major external stressor forced this unsub
讓他需要毫無愧疚地再去殺人
Into feeling the need to kill again without any remorse.
嫌犯的鏡像神經元 加之以往經歷引起的刺激 導致了這起案件
Mirror neurons and stressors Relating to the unsub's past May have triggered this,
這是兩個最主要的因素
The strongest of which is smell.
這個聲音
That sound.
Williams一家在一年前被害
The Williams were killed a year ago.
那時蘭利有沒有什麼大型軍演?
Were there any military maneuvers going on at langley at that time?
每年一度的空軍展 但規模不如今年
The annual air show, but nothing as big as this.
他又行動了 是不是?
he's killed again, hasn't he?
我真幸運啊
Luckily for me.
幸運?
Luckily?
現在就剩我們兩人
Now we're alone.
你說被害人不認識兇手 為什麼?
You stated that the families don't know the killer. why?
現在我們在等待 是不是? 我們倆...
Now we wait, right? you and i,
在等我的仰慕者會不會聯繫我
See if my...admirer contacts me.
他會的
He will.
- 我學的第一個案子就是你的 - 真的?
Yours was one of the first cases i studied. Really?
從此我就迷上了
I've been fascinated ever since.
迷上什麼?
With what?
你
You.
而現在...
And now...
你想知道...我對孩子幹了些什麼
You want to know what i did... To the children.
是不是?
Don't you?
是的
Yes.
我可以演示給你看
I can show you.
我可以完完全全的演示給你看
I can show you exactly what i did to them.
說吧
Tell me.
孩子是如此珍貴
Children are so precious.
如此純潔
So clean.
但同樣需要引導
But they need guidance.
特別是女孩
Especially the girls.
為什麼?
Why?
女孩比男孩更輸得起
Girls have much more to lose... Than boys.
事實也是如此 女性更能忍受痛苦
It's a fact the female body can handle pain much better.
你對他們做了什麼?
What did you do to them?
我向他們演示 男人...
I showed them What men...
他們的父親和哥哥...
Their fathers and brothers...
有什麼本領
Are capable of.
什麼本領?
And what is that?
你確定你想要知道?
You sure you want to know?
是的
Yes.
Morgan 要是刺激兇手的是空演的話
Morgan, if the langley air show is the stressor,
那Karl的仰慕者不符合簡報
Then Karl's admirer doesn't fit the profile.
一個神經病不會炫耀自己是神經病的 Hotch
A psychopath suffering a major psychological break Doesn't brag about it, hotch.
無論你怎麼做 也不可能救得了今天那家人
There was nothing you could have done That would have saved that family today.
要是我做對了側寫就可以
Well, that's if i'm right about the profile.
我希望如此
I think you are.
Karl的仰慕者和案件無關
Karl's admirer doesn't have anything to do with these killings.
無論怎樣 我們都要知道這個仰慕者是誰
Well, either way, we need to know who is.
Hotch 我要你繼續待在那並找出這個人
Hotch, i want you to stay with him and find out
從而制止那畜生
So we can stop this son of a bitch.
知道了
I plan to.
每當我殺了孩子
Once i killed the children,
總讓我感嘆
It always amazed me
他們的父親對於一些不可避免的事情 是多麼蒼白無力
How little... The father fought the inevitable.
什麼事情?
Which was what?
死亡
Dying.
我在搜索william一家的郵件
I'm trolling through the Williams' emails,
衛星電話 家庭電話
Satellite phone calls, land line phone calls,
家庭照片 他們的生活 和其他相關的東西
Family photos, their life, all of it.
Downey一家呢?
What about the downeys?
下一個就是他們 有太多資料了
They're up next, and there's a ton to go through.
- 指紋方面呢 garcia? - 沒有發現
Fingerprints, garcia? zip.
沒有匹配的
They're--they-- there's nothing here.
抱歉 同事們
I'm sorry, folks.
Garcia 擴大搜索範圍
Garcia, widen the search.
Morgan 我已經試過了 暴力犯罪程序堶 包括了國家的所有數據庫
Morgan, i already did. vicap combines every database In this country.
這已經是能做的極限了
we're as wide as we can go.
虐待會給孩子帶來長期陰影
Abuse can have a long-term effect on any child's brain,
但對於那些具有高危基因
But for the abused child who has the high-risk gene
以及眶額腦皮層受過創傷的孩子來說
And the orbital cortex damage,
將帶來不可估量的影響
The combination is devastating.
好了 這次空演是軍方的
All right, this air show is military.
而受害者家的父親都在國外服役
These fathers are all soldiers fighting a war on foreign soil.
我們也知道了這些墳墓並不是贖罪的表現
We know that none of these graves are a sign of remorse.
大家看一下這些墳墓
Hey, guys. look at these graves.
它們看起來像什麼
What are they reminiscent of?
萬人坑
Mass graves.
正是  說明嫌疑犯在他童年的時候
Exactly. which would indicate The unsub experienced early pubescent
曾經目睹了類似的墳墓
3-dimentional mirror neurons
而他的鏡像神經元便反饋給大腦 從而做出類似舉動
Reflecting events similar to the one they're creating.
所以我認為嫌疑犯在戰亂中長大
I think this unsub was born into conflict.
但在哪出生時會伴隨著戰亂呢?
But where was he born into conflict?
大家什麼時候在美國看到過萬人坑?
When was the last time we saw anything like mass graves in the u.s.?
我們這一代沒有目睹過
We haven't. not in our lifetimes.
不是在我們的國土上
Not within our borders.
暴力罪犯程序是全國性的而不是全球性的
Vicap is national, not international.
Garcia 國際數據庫有什麼發現?
Garcia, international databases?
國際刑事警察組織的數據庫是最完善的 要是嫌疑犯有前科 就會有記錄
Interpol is the biggest. if they did it, they're in it.
很明顯他以前犯過案
It's pretty obvious that he's done this before,
問題關鍵是地點和原因
But the question is where and why.
Karl 我從未想過你會如此坦白
Karl, i never thought that you'd be this honest.
每一個誠實男人背後總有一個誘人的女人
It takes a good woman To make an honest man.
不管怎麼說 說白了吧
And anyway, let's face it--
她比你更有吸引力
She's prettier than you.
Karl 你知道你殺害這些人的真正原因麼?
Karl, do you know why you killed all those families?
我已經告訴你了
I've already told you why.
不 你只告訴我用什麼手段 而不是原因
No, you told me how, not why.
而這個案子堨手作案的原因
and the reasons why, in this case,
和你很不一樣
Are very different than they were for you.
完完全全不一樣
they're very, very different.
正如你形象地告訴Prentiss探員的一樣
And as you so eloquently have been pointing out to agent prentiss,
你的動機只是性
All of your motivations were about sex.
你從你父親那學來的動機
Motivations you learned from your father.
你還真在我身上下了功夫
You really have Done your research on me,
Emily
Emily.
我榮幸之至
I'm flattered.
你同樣有著極端的自我仇恨情緒
You're also filled with feelings Of extreme self-hatred.
和這麼個尤物工作一定會分心吧
It must be distracting Working with someone so beautiful.
你強迫他們看著自己的孩子死去
You forced those men to watch their children die,
這就是原因 Karl
And here's why, Karl.
這就是你變成這樣的原因
Here's why you are what you are.
我該怎樣取悅你呢
What i would do to you.
把他們的父親放在最後一個殺害
By killing the fathers last,
你覺得就像在殺害自己的父親一樣
You were killing your own father,
最後輪到你自己
And ultimately yourself,
不斷重複
Over and over again.
這還沒有結束 Hotchner探員 至少對你來說
This isn't over, agent hotchner. At least not for you.
等等 Hotch
Wait, hotch.
Karl的案子堿O父親
For Karl, it's all about the fathers.
這個案子堿O女孩
In this case, it's all about the girls.
他們都是最後死的
They die last.
他們是最後被解決的 都沒受到槍擊
They're laid out last. none of them are shot.
都沒有受到性侵犯
None of them show any signs of sexual motive.
要是這個案子也按照這邏輯?
What if we applied that logic to these killings?
我們沒想到過的線索
That's something we hadn't considered.
怎麼想得到?太少見了
Why would we? it's so rare.
你們在說什麼?
What is?
殺手是女性
The killer's a woman.
- 女性? - 我這就告訴morgan
A woman? i'll let morgan know.
Karl 剛剛你說這件事還沒結束
Karl, just now you said That this wasn't over for me.
你什麼意思?
What did you mean by that?
他只是剛開始熱身
He's just getting warmed up.
只是...
It's just...
你沒看到本質
You don't see it.
但你會的
But you will.
好的 我們現在就辦
All right, we'll work it in right now.
Prentiss認為嫌疑犯可能是女性
Prentiss thinks the unsub might be a woman.
這就是我們找不到性侵犯痕跡的原因
That's why we couldn't find a sexual motive.
不管她是哪的人她父親一定是軍人
Wherever she's from, her father's a military man.
Derek 我從國際刑警組織那找到了線索
Derek, i've got a hit. interpol.
2處吻合 3處吻合 3個作案地點 3 個不同城市
2 hits. 3 hits. 3 crime scenes. 3 different cities.
第一次是在薩格勒布 1998年
The first--zagreb, 1998.
一個女人和她8個月大的孩子遇害
A woman and her 8-month-old baby are both killed.
然後過了兩年
And then 2 years later,
足跡出現在意大利的摩德納
The same prints show up in modena, italy,
隨後在2007 英國倫敦 一對夫婦均中槍身亡
Then 2007, london, england, young couple, both shot.
你們說對了 她有前科
You were right. she's killed before.
薩格勒布是克羅地亞首都
Zagreb is the capital city of croatia.
有什麼大事?
Is that significant?
在91年95年 他們為爭取民族獨立而發動戰爭 (即波黑戰爭,波斯尼亞和黑塞哥維那)
Between 1991 and '95 they fought A bitter battle for independence.
塞爾維亞人曾試圖種族清洗 超過4萬人的波斯尼亞籍穆斯林
Serbian forces tried to ethnically cleanse Over 40,000 bosnian muslims.
接著兩年前 由於某種原因她來到美國
Then at some point within the last 2 years, she moved to america.
- 她不停奔波 - 奔波至一個住滿了軍人家庭的城市
She's on the run. and ran right into a city Filled with military families.
在嫌疑犯心理埋下陰影的萬人坑
The only mass graves reminiscent of the ones the unsubs created
在戰後的波斯尼亞到處都是
Were found all over bosnia after the war,
但都比不上在斯雷佈雷尼察發現的 (波黑一個遭塞族軍隊血洗的城市)
But none of them rival that of srebrenica.
荷蘭的聯合國維和部隊在那建立了難民營
dutch u.n. forces created a safe haven for refugees.
然後在95年 波黑軍隊包圍了斯雷佈雷尼察
then in 1995, bosnian serb forces surrounded the town.
一個精神病患者在這種戰亂下長大
a psychopath born in the middle of that conflict--
太不幸了
That's not a good mix.
她將自己的痛苦經歷強加在受害者身上
she's exacting her life experiences onto the victims.
你認為這個女人當時在場?
You think this woman was there?
想想看吧 蘭利和斯雷佈雷尼察一樣 佈滿了平民和軍用車輛
Well, think about it. langley's filling up with civilians And military vehicles just like srebrenica.
你能判斷出她的年齡嗎?
Can you determine her age?
根據受害者學
Based on victimology,
這些被害女孩的年齡都低於15歲
Each of these girls is no older than 15.
而巴爾幹戰爭從93年持續到95年
The balkan war lasted between '93 and '95,
如果這些女孩代表疑犯
So if the girls represent the unsub,
那麼她應該接近30歲
She's somewhere in her late 20s.
斯雷佈雷尼察最後怎樣了?
how did srebrenica end?
發生了大屠殺
it was a massacre.
(一連串波斯尼亞語 = = )
...
我認為這女人和Karl沒有關聯
i don't think this woman has anything to do with Karl.
我鼓勵他
I encouraged him.
我向他調情
I flirted with him.
把事情弄得很私人
Made it personal.
親近殺手...
Getting intimate with a killer is...
真的很難
So different.
這就是我們的工作
It's what we do.
沒錯 但是...
Yeah. but...
現在我怎麼想都沒用了 是嗎
There's no fixing how i feel right now, is there?
對
No.
但有助解決案件
But it helped the case.
你只是盡自己的職責
And you did what you had to.
Hotchner探員
Agent hotchner.
在你走之前
Before you go,
我還有一件事想和你分享
There's one final thing i'd like to share with you.
我們趕快把這事了結吧
let's just get this over with.
疑犯有武器 遭受過嚴重的精神傷害
This unsub is armed and suffering A major psychological break,
她會毫不猶豫地再開殺戒
And she will not hesitate to kill again.
她是白人 年齡接近30
She's white and in her 20s.
我們認為她在幾年前來到美國
We believe she came to the u.s. a few years ago.
她是步行行動的
She's likely on foot.
可能是東歐人
She could be eastern european.
也許只懂一點英語或完全不會
She may speak little to no english.
要是你們設法逮捕或堵截這個女人
Now, if you manage to apprehend or corner her,
別低估她
Do not underestimate this woman.
她會拚死殺出一條血路
She will try to fight her way out.
Downey家和Forester家相隔不到一英里
The downeys live less than a mile from the foresters,
意味著她就在這區域內的某處
Which means she's somewhere in this area.
好像看到了什麼
I see something.
等等
Wait.
等等 會是這個嗎?
Wait a minute. could it be?
他們都和同一個網站有關
They're all connected to the same site.
已經將現在公眾所面臨的危險知會過媒體
Every media outlet is being informed Of the clear and present danger to the public.
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
夥計們 我有重大發現
ok, guys, i really have got something.
這堛漕C一張照片
All of these photos, every one of them,
都上傳到一個名為"photobug"的網站
Was uploaded to a user website called photobug.
Photobug?
是的 會員可以上傳照片 視頻 郵件
Yeah. members can upload photos, videos, email,
可以在線視頻及聊天 我一直都有在用
Webcam, chats. i use it all the time.
這些家庭都使用這個網站長達數月 甚至數年
Every one of these families extensively used this site For months, even years.
這些家庭照片都是photobug打印出來的
All these family photos were printed by photobug.
難道資料不是受保護的嗎?
Isn't it protected?
對於網站運營商可不是
Not from the people who run it.
這是軍方家屬溝通的好途徑
It's a great way for military families to keep in touch.
也是無需打聽就能鎖定目標的好途徑
And a perfect way to target a family Without anybody's knowledge.
他們把工作分配給國內不同的人
They outsource work to people All over the country.
所以我拿著你的側寫
So i took your profile,
入侵他們的僱員數據庫
Hacked into their employee database,
找出潛在人員的名單
Came up with this list of potentials,
其中一個和這瘋狂的女屠夫吻合
One of which is a match that screams homicidal bitch.
名叫Miranda Dracar 是孤兒
Her name's miranda dracar, she was an orphan,
1982年出生於薩拉熱窩
Born in sarajevo during 1982.
被斯雷佈雷尼察的一個家庭收養
She was adopted by a family in srebrenica.
出發
let's go.
沒人
Clear.
Forester家
The foresters.
Morgan
Morgan.
這是疑犯的下一個目標
The unsub's next victim.
他是海軍士兵
He's a marine.
海軍陸戰隊 第一營 機械師
Usmc, first battalion, engineer.
Jennifer 打電話給聯絡人
Jennifer, call your contact.
長官 我需要授權進入所有與海軍軍士Young相關的數據庫
sir, i'm gonna need access to every piece of data On u.s. marine sergeant young.
這關係到他家人的性命
it may save his family.
你怎麼這麼慢吞吞的 我們要遲到了 快點啊
why are you always so slow? we're late. come on.
知道啦
I am, i am.
你覺得已經找出了我的仰慕者
So you think you found my admirer.
是一個女人
A woman.
不 我們找到的是兇手
No. we found the killer.
無疑是在我的幫助下
With my help, of course.
你的仰慕者和其他聯繫你的人一樣 是失敗者
Your admirer is exactly like everyone who contacts you--lost.
親愛的 你們才失敗啊
My love, your guy is far from lost.
我們完事了
We're done.
他也是
So is he.
"看看我都做了什麼"
"look at what i have done."
真有才啊 不是嗎
It's quite brilliant, you know?
我們會找出是誰寄給你的
We will find whoever sent you that.
不 Hotchner探員 我倒覺得他已經找到你了
No, agent hotchner, i rather think He's already found you.
Morgan?
morgan?
我沒事
I'm all right.
沒事
Hotch
Hotch.
真沒想到啊 你居然看不出他在做什麼
I can't believe you can't see what he's doing.
怎麼了?
What is going on?
他在折磨他
He's torturing him.
誰?
Who?
Hotchner探員 看到你這麼不安真是太爽了
It's great to see you squirm, agent hotchner.
Foyet
Foyet.
他知道你會來的
He knew you'd come.
犯罪心理 第五季 第8集
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds S05E08